Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1962-1963
  - "Unfair Comment: A Warning to News Media", 1962 Fall (Box-folder 272: 2)
  - "Habeas Proprietatem: Due Process for International Investments: A Prior Consideration for Investments Abroad, 1963 June (Box-folder 272: 3)
- Children, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 272: 4-5)
- Iraq and occupied Kuwait, 1990 (Box-folder 272: 6)
- Fang Lizhi, 1990 (Box-folder 272: 7)
- Moise Tshombe case, 1967 (Box-folder 272: 8)
- Correspondence, 1983-1991
  - Alex Fusailoff, 1990 (Box-folder 272: 9)
  - Holocaust Memorial Foundation of Illinois, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 272: 10)
  - Clinton A. Krislov, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 272: 11)
- Emile Gauguin, 1992 (Box-folder 273: 1)
- Pre-marital and pre-natal screening, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 273: 2)
- Correspondence, 1984-1992
  - Phyllis Carlyle, 1989 (Box-folder 273: 3)
  - Susan J. Cohen, 1991 (Box-folder 273: 4)
  - Peter J. Conley, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 273: 5)
  - Eric Cox, 1992 (Box-folder 273: 4)
  - Jim Dolan, 1989 (Box-folder 273: 7)
  - Max Frankel, 1988 (Box-folder 273: 8)
  - Global Justice, 1991 (Box-folder 273: 9)
  - William S. Kroger, Jr., 1992 (Box-folder 273: 10)
  - Shanmughasundaram Mohan, 1991 (Box-folder 273: 11)
  - Daniel Patrick Moynihan, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 273: 14)
  - George H. Ryan, 1988 (Box-folder 273: 13)
  - Charles Rhyne, 1991 (Box-folder 273: 14)
  - Veterans Assistance Commission of Cook County, 1985 (Box-folder 273: 15)
  - Burns H. Weston, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 273: 16)
  - Boris Yeltsin, 1991 (Box-folder 273: 17)
- Abused women, 1991 (Box-folder 274: 1)
  - Gene th
- Burma, 1993 (Box-folder 274: 2)
- Agatha Christie, 1990 (Box-folder 274: 3)
- Winston Churchill, 1965-1991 (Box-folder 274: 4)
- Kuwait, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 274: 5)
- Mozambique, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 274: 6)
- Salman Rushdie, 1992 (Box-folder 274: 7)
- Stevenson family, 1989 (Box-folder 274: 8)
- Correspondence, 1989-1993
  - Assyrian Universal Alliance, 1991 (Box-folder 274: 9)
  - Louis René Beres, 1991 (Box-folder 274: 10)
  - Joan Brown, 1991 (Box-folder 274: 11)
  - Philip H. Corboy and Thomas A. Demetrio, 1990 (Box-folder 274: 12)
  - Morris Dees, 1991 (Box-folder 274: 13)
  - Noah Hanft, 1990 (Box-folder 274: 14)
  - Wendy S. Klein, 1991 (Box-folder 274: 15)
  - George J. Mitchell, 1990 (Box-folder 274: 16)
  - Hal Polaire, 1989 (Box-folder 274: 17)
  - Alfred P. Rubin, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 274: 18)
  - Stephanos Stavros, 1990 (Box-folder 274: 19)
  - Donna Storseth, 1989 (Box-folder 274: 20)
  - Telford Taylor, 1992 (Box-folder 274: 21)
  - Isaac and Leonard Wolfson, 1991 (Box-folder 274: 22)
- Bio-ontogeny therapy center, 1986 (Box-folder 275: 1)
- Jack Ruby, 1978 (Box-folder 275: 2)
- Michael Egan, 1990 (Box-folder 275: 3)
- Fiji, 1990 (Box-folder 275: 4)
- Ernest Hemingway, 1992 (Box-folder 275: 5)
- Bosnia-Herzegovina, 1992 (Box-folder 275: 6)
- Correspondence, 1990-1992
  - Lord Shawcross, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 275: 7)
  - Sol Spiegel, 1990 (Box-folder 275: 8)
  - World Federalist Association, 1992 (Box-folder 275: 9)
- Trademarks, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 276: 1)
- Bio-ontogeny venture, 1986 (Box-folder 276: 2)
- Jane M. Byrne, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 277: 1)
- Gene therapy, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 277: 2)
- Datebook, 1984 (Box-folder 278: 1)
- Address book
- Miscellaneous clippings, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 278: 3)
- Tibet, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 278: 4)
- Datebooks, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 279: 1-2)
- China and Fang Lizhi, 1989 (Box-folder 279: 3)
- Miscellaneous clippings, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 280: 1-2)
- Biographical materials relating to Luis Kutner, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 280: 3)
- Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organization Act, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 280: 4-5)
- Rule 2-611, 1987 (Box-folder 280: 6)
- Guy Lombardo, 1984 (Box-folder 281: 1)
- Freedom Legal Aid Group, 1984 (Box-folder 281: 2)
- Chernobyl, 1988 (Box-folder 281: 3)
- Nobel Peace Prize nomination, 1972 (Box-folder 281: 4)
- Correspondence, 1983-1993
  - Jamila Ife Asia, 1984 (Box-folder 281: 5)
  - Gregory Bautzer, 1984 (Box-folder 281: 6)
  - David Berger, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 281: 7)
  - Richard J. Conviser, 1983 (Box-folder 281: 8)
  - Ernest Katin, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 281: 9)
  - Robert S. Mendelsohn, 1984 (Box-folder 281: 10)
  - Harry Winefield, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 281: 11)
  - Paul Ziffren, 1983 (Box-folder 281: 12)
- Franchising, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 282: 1)
- Horses, 1980 (Box-folder 282: 2)
- Croatia, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 282: 3)
- Korean Air Lines Flight 007, 1983 (Box-folder 282: 4)
- Puerto Rico, 1983 (Box-folder 282: 5)
- Lebanon, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 282: 6)
- Correspondence, 1983-1988
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 282: 7)
  - Georgia M. Gabor, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 282: 8)
  - Fran Goodwin, 1983 (Box-folder 282: 9)
  - Bernard and Marge Mitchell, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 282: 10)
  - Linda M. Parks, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 282: 11)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 282: 12)
- Laurence Olivier, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 283: 1)
- Anatoly Shcharansky, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 283: 2)
- Angel Cuadra and Cuba, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 283: 3)
- Correspondence, 1969-1990
  - N. E. Ajagwu, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 4)
  - Felicitas S. Aquino, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 5)
  - Mario Biaggi, 1975-1988 (Box-folder 283: 6)
  - Thomas J. Dodd, 1969 (Box-folder 283: 7)
  - George C. Marshall Foundation, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 283: 8)
  - Neil Hartigan, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 283: 9)
  - Hofstra Law Review Association, 1984 (Box-folder 283: 10)
  - Lawyer of the Americas, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 11)
  - William Lichtman, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 12)
  - Marcy Permut, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 13)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 14)
  - Mary S. Roebling, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 283: 15)
  - Sierra Club Legal Defense Club, 1984 (Box-folder 283: 16)
  - Joseph T. Stasiak, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 17)
  - Orpha Raglin Welke, 1983 (Box-folder 283: 18)
- Iraq and Saddam Hussein, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 284: 1)
- Correspondence, 1982-1992
  - Edward E. Henry, 1982 (Box-folder 284: 2)
  - Caro Martin, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 284: 3)
- Denver World Advocates Center, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 285: 1)
- Kurds, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 285: 2)
- Correspondence, 1975-1987
  - American Bar Association, 1978 (Box-folder 286: 1)
  - Freedom House, 1987 (Box-folder 286: 2)
  - Michigan Mutual Insurance, 1975-1983 (Box-folder 286: 3)
  - PItney Bowes, 1982 (Box-folder 286: 4)
  - William J. Scott, 1978 (Box-folder 286: 5)
- Auto license, 1967-1986 (Box-folder 286: 6)
- Camp David Accords, 1987 (Box-folder 286: 7)
- Tibet, 1988 (Box-folder 286: 8)
- Charles Glass, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 287: 1)
- Solar energy, 1982 (Box-folder 287: 2)
- Philadelphia World Trade Center, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 3)
- Tunisia, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 287: 4)
- Correspondence, 1987-1992
  - Annette Bennette and Sol Polk, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 5)
  - Bruce E. Briley, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 287: 6)
  - Frank Butler, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 7)
  - Hill and Knowlton, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 8)
  - John Kourvas, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 9)
  - Lee Miglin, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 10)
  - Nemesio E. Prudente, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 11)
  - Robert S. Ruwitch, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 12)
  - Erich H. Sontag, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 287: 13)
  - James Michael Thunder, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 287: 14)
  - Jeannie Tucker, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 15)
  - University of Detroit Law Review, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 287: 16)
  - Seigon H. Yamaoka, 1987 (Box-folder 287: 17)
- Protocols of the Elders of Zion, 1987 (Box-folder 288: 1)
- Correspondence, 1987-1993
  - Harry F. Chaddick, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 288: 2)
  - Wolfgang Jöchle, 1987 (Box-folder 288: 3)
  - Philip Klutznick, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 288: 4)
  - George Lane, 1992
  - Laurie-Anne Ramsey and Scott Aaron, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 288: 6)
  - Steven T. Rosen, 1988 (Box-folder 288: 7)
  - Ezra J. Scheff, 1988 (Box-folder 288: 8)
  - Paul Simon, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 288: 9)
  - Lairold M. Street, 1987 (Box-folder 288: 9)
  - Peter Weiss, 1987 (Box-folder 288: 11)
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1980-1991
  - "Self-Motivation: Self-Discovery for Peace of Mind", 1980 (Box-folder 289: 1)
  - Poetry, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 289: 2)
- Correspondence, 1987-1989
  - Chavez, Danny, 1987 (Box-folder 289: 3)
  - Winston P. Nagan, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 289: 4)
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1970-1975
  - The Intelligent Woman's Guide to Future Security, 1970 (Box-folder 290: 1-4)
  - "The Dust of Love", 1975 (Box-folder 290: 5-6)
  - "Green Dust", 1975 (Box-folder 291: 1-2)
- American Jewish Ledger, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 291: 3-6)
- Amparo, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 292: 1)
- Arctic sovereignty, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 292: 2)
- Background materials for speeches, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 292: 4)
- Correspondence, 1975-1992
  - Harold Copeland, 1986 (Box-folder 292: 5)
  - Francis R. Dobrowski, 1985 (Box-folder 292: 6)
  - Robert A. Friedlander, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 292: 7)
  - Mady Gerrard Gaston, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 292: 8)
  - Mary Hill, 1985 (Box-folder 292: 9)
  - Joseph N. Hosteny, 1986 (Box-folder 292: 10)
  - Donald L. Johnson, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 292: 11)
  - Ruth Mundy Kelly, 1986 (Box-folder 292: 12)
  - Romik M. Kesian, 1986 (Box-folder 292: 13)
  - Neal S. Mankarious, 1986 (Box-folder 292: 14)
  - Michael Posner, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 292: 15)
  - Ralph M. Vicinanza, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 292: 16)
  - Chesna Weinberg, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 292: 17)
  - Hubert L. Will, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 292: 18)
- Benazir Bhutto, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 293: 1)
- Ludmilla Boreisha, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 293: 2)
- George Bernard Shaw, 1950-1985 (Box-folder 293: 3)
- United Koreans Assembly, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 4)
- Whales, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 293: 5)
- Correspondence, 1985-1987
  - Paul A. Kolpak, 1986 (Box-folder 293: 6)
  - Delwyn Marquette, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 7)
  - Ed Pearl, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 8)
  - Philip A. Prossnitz, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 9)
  - Roman Pucinski, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 10)
  - Michael J. Rosanova, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 11)
  - Don Shelley, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 12)
  - Margaret Thatcher, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 13)
  - Sanford G. Thatcher, 1985 (Box-folder 293: 14)
- Iran, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 294: 1)
- United Veterans Assembly, 1985 (Box-folder 294: 2-3)
- Correspondence, 1983-1990
  - Paul R. Doyle, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 294: 4)
  - Kenneth R. Redden, 1985 (Box-folder 294: 5)
  - Randolph W. Ringstad, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 294: 6)
- Writing by Luis Kutner, "The Straight Jacket of 1982" (Box-folder 295: 1)
- Captive nations, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 295: 2)
- Nazis, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 295: 3)
- Coptic Church, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 296: 1-2)
- Iran, 1989 (Box-folder 296: 3)
- Correspondence, 1981-1991
  - Robert F. Groshon, 1984 (Box-folder 296: 4)
  - Ed Kelly, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 296: 5)
  - W. Michael Reisman, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 296: 6)
  - Marilyn Salchert, 1984 (Box-folder 296: 7)
  - Robin E. Jasper Wessel, 1982 (Box-folder 296: 8)
  - World Order Under Law, 1984 (Box-folder 296: 9)
- Drexel Burnham Lambert, 1988 (Box-folder 297: 1)
- United States of America v. Ferdinand E. Marcos, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 297: 2)
- Correspondence, 1987-1992
  - R. J. Rummel, 1992 (Box-folder 297: 3)
  - Helen Solem, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 298: 1)
  - Jerrold Wexler, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 298: 2)
- Somalia, 1988 (Box-folder 299: 1)
- Correspondence, 1987-1993
  - Mairin Higgins, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 299: 2)
  - Hoover Institution, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 299: 3)
- Due process, 1982 (Box-folder 300: 1)
- Zimbabwe, 1988 (Box-folder 300: 2)
- India, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 300: 3)
- Zia ul-Haq, 1988 (Box-folder 300: 4)
- Allen Dorfman, 1988 (Box-folder 300: 5)
- Correspondence, 1982-1990
  - Monica Ambrose and Arthur Phillips, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 300: 6)
  - Kimberly Bell, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 300: 7)
  - Herb Kraus, 1988 (Box-folder 300: 8)
  - Max Samter, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 300: 9)
  - Marguerite Vignon, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 300: 10)
- Biotherapeutics, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 1)
- William Casey, 1987 (Box-folder 301: 2)
- Ildyko Elofsson, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 301: 3)
- Norman Kean, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 4)
- Soviet Union, 1987 (Box-folder 301: 5)
- Orson Welles, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 6)
- Elie Wiesel, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 7)
- Correspondence, 1987-1992
  - Nina Appel, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 8)
  - Ruth Duskin Feldman, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 9)
  - Benjamin Ferencz, 1991 (Box-folder 301: 10)
  - Peter Hall, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 11)
  - Harold Haydon, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 301: 12)
  - Julia Heflin, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 301: 13)
  - Leona Helmsley, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 14)
  - Steven L. Jacobs, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 15)
  - Ruth Lapidoth, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 301: 16)
  - Charles N. Mahjoubian, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 301: 17)
  - Jay Richmond, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 301: 18)
  - Gwen Sterk, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 19)
  - Carlos Xavier, 1988 (Box-folder 301: 20)
- Israel, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 302: 1)
- Correspondence, 1987-1993
  - Francis A. Boyle, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 302: 2)
  - Concern for Dying, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 302: 3)
  - Martha D. Moore, 1988 (Box-folder 302: 4)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1988 (Box-folder 1988)
  - Robbie Sabel, 1991 (Box-folder 302: 6)
- Horses, 1983 (Box-folder 303: 1)
- Correspondence, 1981-1991
  - Roland I. Pritikin, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 303: 2)
  - Society for the Right to Die, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 303: 3)
  - Society for the Right to Die, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 304: 1-3)
- Miscellany, 1984 (Box-folder 305: 1)
- John Hinckley, 1985 (Box-folder 305: 2)
- Living will, 1985 (Box-folder 305: 3)
- Ireland, Northern Ireland, and Irish Americans, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 306: 1-2)
- Idi Amin, 1978 (Box-folder 306: 3)
- Idi Amin, 1977-1992 (Box-folder 307: 1)
- Kim Il Sung, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 307: 2)
- Correspondence, 1972-1988
  - Larry Adler, 1984 (Box-folder 307: 3)
  - William F. Buckley, Jr., 1984 (Box-folder 307: 4)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1983 (Box-folder 307: 5)
  - Ronald Reagan, 1988 (Box-folder 307: 6)
  - Slava Stetsko, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 307: 7)
  - Valparaiso University Law Review, 1972-1987 (Box-folder 307: 8)
  - MIscellaneous correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 307: 9)
- Kangwane, 1984 (Box-folder 308: 1)
- Thailand, 1984 (Box-folder 308: 2)
- Correspondence, 1983-1986
  - Don Barnes, 1986 (Box-folder 308: 3)
  - Jong Park, 1983 (Box-folder 308: 4)
  - Thomas Wahl, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 308: 5)
- Framed article about Luis Kutner and world habeas corpus proposal, 1964 (Box-folder 309: 1)